[MUSIC].
Well, welcome to the end of week zero.
for each week, I'll create a video for
the week's mini project.
And I'll walk you through the details of
how to create that mini project.
Most of the mini projects will be between
50 to 150 lines of Python code.
However, the first mini project we're
going to do is going to be very easy.
It's just one line of Python code.
And it's really designed to help you
learn how to create, submit and peer
evaluate your mini projects.
It's totally optional.
If you feel confident, you can follow
instructions, feel free to skip this.
If you think it's silly, feel free to
skip it.
before I go onto there though, I'm going
to answer two important questions.
First, why would anybody name a computer
lang, language after a giant snake?
It's Python.
Everybody says, well what's Python?
It's a snake.
Well, no, it's named after something
different.
It's named after Monty Python's Flying
Circus.
So, Monty Python's Flying Circus is a
British comedy troupe.
And there's a kind of a, a tradition in
the Python community to have inside
references to material from Monty
Python's skits and movies.
our project is based on inside reference
to the movie, Monty Python and the Holy
Grail.
And they're knights of King Arthur,
members of the Python comedy troupe, and
they go out and interact with the Knights
Who Say Ni.
And I'll let you kind of dig around on
the web, if you want to find out more
information.
But the phrase, we want a shrubbery,
comes up in that particular scene.
the second question that you might
want to ask is who's this?
This is Sir Loin.
I'm the chair of the Department of
Computer Science here at Rice and I
inherited Sir Loin.
This is really his name.
I was told specifically this is his name.
Five years ago, whenever I took over as
chair.
And for five years he's set here and I
have no clue what to do with him.
So, I decided for this video, what the
heck.
He'll be my co-host.
And actually, he'll weigh on in, weigh in
on an important topic later in this
video.
So anyways, let's go out now and get
serious and we'll talk about how to
create, submit and peer assess your mini
projects.
All right, let's walk through the process
of creating, submitting and peer assesing
your mini project.
So, we'll start here at the main class
page.
Over here, we have the Nav bar, which has
all the entries for various class
material and activities.
And now, the three most important ones
are Video Lectures, Quizzes and
Mini-projects.
So, kind of at the start of each week, go
out here, you'll click on Mini-projects
and you'll see here, it's kind of an
overview of how the process works for
submitting and assessing a mini-project.
And at the bottom, you'll see the links
for the various mini-projects you have
waiting.
So, here, for example, we have two
current mini-projects out.
This is the one for the end of week zero.
We want a shrubbery, that's optional.
You don't have to turn it in, just there
for you to figure out how peer assessment
works.
And the second one, this is the one
you're going to turn in, it's the end of
week one.
It'll be Rock-paper-scissor-lizard-Spock.
Now, kind of, one of the things that
comes up is when are these due?
So, we have one uniform time for the
entire class when everything is due,
quizzes, mini-projects, everything.
And that is 0500 Greenwich Median Time.
Now, because everybody works on their own
local time, you've got to figure out when
is that for you.
So, Coursera, Coursera has has support
for this.
So, the first thing I want you to do, is
go up to your Settings.
Up here, pull down, and make sure your
Timezone is set correctly.
So, I'm in the Chicago timezone.
So, I'm actually in Houston, so
everything is fine there.
And now, you can pull down here.
And you can see that it says, well
everything is due midnight Saturday in
Houston.
So, that's actually 500 Greenwich Median
Time.
And if you pull this button over, you can
actually see kind of the time dates for
both submission, peer assessment, and
then getting back the results.
So, you're going to have about three and
a half days to do peer assessment in
there.
so my kind of suggestion is, since it's
going to due in the middle of the weekend
on a middle of the weekend, my suggestion
is start early.
And then, you've got Saturday to kind of
work on doing the current week's
assignment.
And then, you can kind of take a glance
at the upcoming weeks assignment when
it's released.
Okay.
Let's go on and we'll look at the
specific assignment.
Okay, let's go walk through building your
first mini-project.
So, we'll go to this page, we'll say,
click Go To Assignment.
And, actually, up pops the webpage for
the assignment.
At the top, you can see kind of three
button, three things here.
These correspond to the submission phase,
which is we're in right now.
There'll be a peer evaluation phase.
And there'll be a phase where you see the
results.
So, I'm actually recording this video
well before class starts.
We scroll down here, we'll see kind of
the start of descriptions of the
mini-project.
the main thing in this particular
mini-project is to walk through the
logistics side.
A fairly detailed description of exactly
what we're talking about.
One thing to note here is that the
mini-project is always released at 0500
Greenwich Mean Time on a Saturday
morning.
So, that means you have exactly eight
days to work on your mini-projects.
So, if you get done early, you have an
entire weekend to work on it.
You have the following week, and you have
another day there.
So, If you work very effectively, you
have a good bit of time to work on the
mini-projects.
if you scroll on down, you see kind of
the rest of what we're going to talk
about here.
One thing to note here is we have a save
service available for CodeSkulptor.
For some reason, save doesn't work in
CodeSkulptor.
We've had that occasion with students
from some countries that block access to
Google storage.
You can use this link and have another
route in to actually generate a
CodeSculptor URL that you can submit for
your mini-project.
let's scroll on down.
For most of your assignments, this will
be kind of the meat of what you'll see.
You'll see a little introduction.
And then, you'll see what I'm going to
refer to as a mini-project development
process.
And that's going to be very detailed.
It's going to walk you through how to
build your mini-project step by step.
It's important you read it.
To help you get through these
mini-projects, we are going to give you
very detailed advice and recommendations.
I had way too many students in previous
sessions of the class ignore this and
say, I can do it on my own.
And then, at the end, they get stuck, and
they come say, oh my gosh, what's going
on.
I can't do this.
I ask, did you follow the development
process, and they go no.
So, use this, it's here to help you.
and then, the second thing I want to
point out is that there's a grading
rubric attached to this.
So, as you're working on the project,
we'll tell you exactly what your project
needs to do.
You're going to have questions such as,
does my project need to do x?
Well, look at the grading rubric.
The grading rubric is going to have
there, have a, on this case, probably
about 15 to 25 items that will determine
whether your project works correctly or
not.
And they're going to be very small part,
either you get a point or you won't.
So, for example, down here, one of rubric
items says the program prints a message
in the console.
Okay, if your program does it, you get a
point.
If your program doesn't, you won't.
so go through and take a look at this.
when you're actually ready to start
working on your mini-project.
Where it's going to provide you with a
program template.
And then, it will be a CodeSkulptor file
that you can start from, that provides
kind of a code base for getting working
on your project.
Currently, any mini-projects, it's not so
critical.
You can probably do it from scratch.
But when you start working on some of the
projects later in the class, we're going
to give you a lot of useful things.
For example, when you do rice rocks at
the end of the class, we're going to give
you all the art and sound assets.
So, that template's going to contain
information about how to get your hands
on this.
So, we'll just go through and do this
mini-project really quickly.
So, I'm going to click on this, and up
popped CodeSkulptor and what we see here.
You know, here's CodeSkulptor, we got
some comments.
But most importantly, here we see, print
hello world.
So, this mini-project is really easy, we
just have to change this to print.
We want a shrubbery, so let's do that.
[SOUND] Now, let's not forget our dots, a
shrubbery.
Let's run it really quick, looks pretty
good.
We can go back here and let's take a peek
at the grading rubric again.
Same number of dots.
Looks pretty good.
So, let's go into CodeSkulptor.
Now, we can hit Save.
And notice now, it generated a fresh
CodeSkulptor URL here.
So, this is unique for your particular
solution.
So now, when we're ready to submit this,
all we do is the following.
You select the URL.
Ctrl+C to copy, we go down and we Paste
it in this box.
That's all you do.
You don't cut and paste a version of your
program in here.
Cutting and pasting entire pieces of
programs is very tricky.
What happens is if somebody who's
creating your project actually doesn't
get an entire project?
Your'e going to be upset.
So, the critical thing here is only
submit a CodeSkulptor URL, don't submit
your program in here.
When you're happy with it, click the
Honor Code button.
Notice what that did.
That actually highlighted this button,
Submit for grading.
Okay.
So, a lot of the time I see people say, I
can't figure out how to submit it.
This button, yeah, this button isn't
highlighted for me.
You have to click this box that says, I
agree to the honor code.
When you're ready to submit it for
grading, click Submit for grading.
And there it is.
We've now submitted your, submitted your
code for grading.
So, a couple things about submission.
if you decide, wow, you know, I submitted
it early and I wanted to go back and work
on it some more because I realized it was
a mistake or I was a little bit, kind of
worried I was going to get it done in
time.
It's perfectly fine to cut an paste a new
URL in your corresponding to a new
assignment and resubmit it.
There's no penalty for submitting as much
as you want.
If you're getting close to the deadline
and you think, oh man, the deadline
passed,Coursera has a very, very generous
policy on late submission.
There's a great grace period.
So, if you're a couple of minutes past
the deadline, don't panic.
Just go through and submit it.
I think most of the time, you've got a,
you've got a fair bit of time to do it.
I want to emphasize one thing.
You have to click the Submit button.
If you click Save, your project will not
be submitted for grading.
Saving your project does not get it
submitted for, for grading in pure
assessment.
This is probably the biggest thing I can
say with this one video.
Click Submit.
If you don't click Submit, you'll be very
sad when you find out that you're not
going to be able to do peer assessment
and get your own project assessed by your
peers.
Hit Submit.
Okay.
Now, let's go out and take a look at peer
assessment.
Okay, let's walk through the process of
peer evaluation.
So, an hour after the mini-project is
due, the peer assessment page is open.
And so, if you go back to assignment
page, this tab will be active.
And in particular, if you click on this
link, you'll be directed to five pages,
one with one for each of five of your
peers.
Your job would to be go through and take
those peers projects and assess them
based on the grading rubic that we
provided.
You'll then, be asked to evaluate your
own project and do self assessment.
So, if we scroll down, we're actually
working on the first student.
Now, because this is before we've
actually started peer evaluations, this
box is empty, but this box will contain
the URL for your peer's assignment.
below, we'll have kind of a form that
you'll need to do to actually do the
evaluation.
We'll ask you two questions to start.
What kind of operating system does your
computer have and what kind of browser
did you use, in case there's some issue
with some of the, how your peer
assessment actually came out.
here are the grading instructions.
And this essentially kind of leads into
the four rubric items we talked about.
This is here, the first rubric item.
If we submit a valid CodeSkulptor URL,
and then we have some options for this,
and then we have a place to submit some
comments.
So, actually, let's go through and do it.
I actually have a URL, so I'm sitting
here in CodeSkulptor, I'm going to paste
it in.
And let's hit Enter.
And sure enough, up comes the project we
just did, that we just created.
So, it looks like that's a valid
CodeSkulptor URL.
So, I'm going to go through here and say
1.
And because it worked, I'm not going to
put any comments in.
See, running the program does not throw
an error.
Let's do that.
So, I'll run it.
No errors, looks good.
Let's go back and give them a 1.
Keep going.
It says prints a message in the console.
Yeah, printed a message in the console,
good job.
Okay.
Let's keep going down.
Last, prints the following message, we
want a shrubbery.
Okay.
Well, let's see, run it again.
We got, we want dot, dot, dot a shrubery.
Hmm, uh-oh, wait a misspelled shrubbery.
Hmm, let's go back.
It says, we want a shrubbery.
It says, prints the specified message.
Now, if you were having this machine
graded, you'd be out of luck.
But we're using humans.
So, humans have the ability to make
judgments.
And one of the judgments is that, that
your peers satisfy the spirit of this
rubric eye.
Remember, we're all here to learn.
So, I'm going to ask Sir Loin.
Sir Loin, did they need the spirit of
this rubric item?
Well, Sir Loin being part of King
Arthur's round table as merciful?
And he says yes, he did.
So, I'm going to give him full credit.
But, I'm going to make a note here that
you misspelled shrubbery.
It's always good if you're, either
there's an issue or you take off points
to add a comment here.
Just think how it is.
It's very frustrating if you get points
marked off of your project and there's no
reason given.
So, take a few seconds and put in a
message here, if there's some issue with
the project on a particular item.
then you get a chance to get some overall
feedback here.
Remember, this should be positive.
Your goal is not to make your peers feel
bad.
It's to give helpful advice.
you did a great job inside, outside of
spelling.
There you go.
And this point now, you can submit your
evaluation.
Once you've done that, Coursera will prop
you, prompt you to go off and do four
more students, and do this same process
of filling in forms.
For most mini-projects, it should take at
most an hour.
You spend maybe 10 minutes on each one.
That gives you, basically you have to do
five of your peers, and then you have to
do yourself.
That's about an hour worth of work.
the better job you do, hopefully your
peers will do a good job on your project.
One caveat.
You gotta hit Submit.
You can't get to the next projects until
you hit Submit.
So doing your peers is usually pretty
easy, people don't mess that up.
But you're in a hurry to get finished,
and you're doing a self assessment and
you forget to hit Submit.
What happens?
Well, Coursera says you didn't do your
self assessment.
And the way the grading is setup and we
can't change this, this is Course, this
is the way Coursera works, is you get a
20% fiddle if you fail to do peer
assessment or self assessment.
So, please, remember to hit Submit.
It's painful to lose 20% of your hard
earned grade because you forget to hit
Submit evaluation.
Okay, go out there and give it a crack,
our work through logistics.
This isn't for a grade, so this is your
chance to make some errors and learn how
to do it correctly next week when we do
rock, paper, scissors, lizard, spock.
Okay, see you then.